Imagine spending seven years at MIT and research laboratories,
تخيلوا قضاء سبع سنوات في معهد ماساتشوستس للتكنولوجيا ومختبرات البحوث ،
only to find out that you're a performance artist.
فقط لمعرفة انك فنان.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I'm also a software engineer,
أنا أيضا مهندس برمجيات ،
and I make lots of different kinds of art with the computer.
وأنا أصنع الكثير من الأنواع المختلفة للفنون بإستخدام الكمبيوتر.
And I think the main thing that I'm interested in
واعتقد ان الشيء الرئيسي الذي أنا مهتم به
is trying to find a way of
هو محاولة ايجاد وسيلة ل
making the computer into a personal mode of expression.
جعل الكمبيوتر في وضعية تعبّر عن الشخصية.
And many of you out there are the heads of Macromedia and Microsoft,
وكثير منكم أنتم هناك هم رؤساء ماكروميديا ، ومايكروسوفت ،
and in a way those are my bane:
وبطريقة أولئك يمهدون الطريق لي :
I think there's a great homogenizing force
اعتقد ان هناك قوة عظيمة متجانسة
that software imposes on people and limits the way they think
أن البرامج تُفرض على الناس وتحد من طريقة تفكيرهم
about what's possible on the computer.
حول ما هو ممكن على الكمبيوتر.
Of course, it's also a great liberating force that makes possible,
بطبيعة الحال ، أنها قوة عظمى تحرر الطاقات التي تجعل الأمر ممكناً،
you know, publishing and so forth, and standards, and so on.
تعرفون ، النشر ، والخ...، والمعايير ، وهلم جرا.
But, in a way, the computer makes possible much more
ولكن ،بطريقة ما ،الكمبيوتر يجعل من الممكن أكثر من ذلك بكثير
than what most people think, and my art has just been about
مما يعتقد معظم الناس ، وفني قد كان فقط حول
trying to find a personal way of using the computer,
محاولة لايجاد وسيلة شخصية باستخدام الحاسوب ،
and so I end up writing software to do that.
وهكذا أنا أنهيت كتابة برنامج للقيام بذلك.
Chris has asked me to do a short performance,
كريس قد طلب مني القيام بأداء قصير ،
and so I'm going to take just this time -- maybe 10 minutes --
وهكذا سأستفيد من هذا الوقت -- ربما عشر دقائق --
to do that, and hopefully at the end have just a moment
للقيام بذلك ، ونأمل في النهاية ان يكون لدينا فقط لحظة
to show you a couple of my other projects in video form.
لأظهر لكم بعض مشاريعي الأخرى في شكل فيديو.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق).
We've got about a minute left.
لدينا حوالي دقيقة متبقية.
I'd just like to show a clip from a most recent project.
انني اريد أن أعرض مقطع من مشروع حديث .
I did a performance with two singers
لقد أديته مع اثنين من المغنين
who specialize in making strange noises with their mouths.
متخصصون في صنع أصوات غريبة بأفواههم.
And this just came off last September at ARS Electronica;
وهذا فقط خرج في سبتمبر الماضي في آرس إليكترونيكا ؛
we repeated it in England.
كررنا ذلك في انكلترا.
And the idea is to visualize their speech and song behind them
والفكرة هي أن تصور كلامهما وغنائهما ورائهما
with a large screen.
مع وجود شاشة كبيرة.
We used a computer vision tracking system
اعتدنا رؤية الكمبيوتر في نظام التتبع
in order to know where they were.
من أجل معرفة مكان وجودهما.
And since we know where their heads are,
ونظرا لأننا نعرف أين رؤوسهما ،
and we have a wireless mic on them
ولدينا ميكروفون لاسلكي عليهما
that we're processing the sound from,
الذي نجهّزالصوت عبره ،
we're able to create visualizations
نحن قادرون على خلق تصورات
which are linked very tightly to what they're doing with their speech.
التي ترتبط بتماسك شديد مع ما يفعلونه بخطابهم.
This will take about 30 seconds or so.
سوف هذا يستغرق نحو 30 ثانية أو نحو ذلك.
He's making a, kind of, cheek-flapping sound.
انه يصنع، نوع من ،صوت خفقان الخدود.
Well, suffice it to say it's not all like that, but that's part of it.
حسنا، يكفي ان نقول انها ليست كلها من هذا القبيل ، ولكن هذا جزء منها.
Thanks very much. There's always lots more.
شكرا جزيلا. هناك دائما الكثير.
I'm overtime, so I just wanted to say you can, if you're in New York,
لقد تجاوزت الوقت ،لذا أريد فقط أن أقول لكم يمكنكم ، إذا كنتم في نيويورك ،
you can check out my work at the Whitney Biennial next week,
يمكنكم أن تتحققوا من عملي في بينالي ويتني الاسبوع المقبل ،
and also at Bitforms Gallery in Chelsea.
وأيضا في معرض بتفورمز غاليريا في تشيلسي.
And with that, I think I should give up the stage,
ومع ذلك ، أعتقد أنني يجب أن أترجل من المسرح،
so, thank you so much.
لذلك ، شكرا جزيلا.